HITESH BORSE

Software Engineer(2.5+ years)

SUMMARY

Software Engineer well-versed in full stack development with total experience of 2.5+ years. I have worked on web projects for creating responsive web designs, CRUD operations, created multiple reusable components for frontend using React JS and also provided backend support using Node.js for SQL and NoSQL Databases.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, Iconnect info Solutions

07/2021 - Present

DV INVESTMENT (WEB APP)

Navi Mumbai

Duration: July 2021 - March 2022

Role: Full stack developer

• Technologies: NodeJS, React.js, Context Api, MySql, Prisma Orm, DigitalOcean

• Website link : https://dvia.in/

· Responsibility:

Worked on a frontend which was created using React.js, Context API Used CSS flex for designing.

Created reusable components, responsive tables, downloads

Created various forms and validations using Formik

Worked on a backend which was created using node.js, express.js

Used Prisma ORM to communicate with MySql database for crud operations.

Frontend Developer

03/2022 - 04/2022

KIKODA (WEB APP)

UK

• Technologies: React.js, Redux, Kendo React UI Lib, Microfrontend architechture.

· Responsibility:

Debugging and feature updates related working for frontend side.

Basically its a insurance related web portal whose frontend is managed in react, js with help of microfrontend architecture.

Used React redux to manage data stores.

Insurance related forms which we have developed in this portal are develope with the help of react-hook-form along with kendo react UI Lib support.

Frontend developer

05/2022 - 09/2022

ZBYTE (WEB APP)

Pune

• Technologies: Next.is, Context API, Material UI Lib, micro frontends

Responsibility:

A webApp based on blockchain technology.

Worked on frontend, which was created using React.js, Redux and monolithic micro frontend technology.

Worked to integrate Survey monkey integration

UI development of Polls section along with NFT.

Implemented offers management section to attach offers with NFTs for admin dashboard using Azure blob storage to store offers related assets

Frontend Developer

09/2022 - 09/2023

ORCICARE (WEB APP)

US

- Technologies: React, Redux, context-API, material UI, AWS
- Website link: https://billing-web-test.services.orcicare.com/
- Responsibility:

Implemented chat messaging feature

Implementation of a timesheet management system for employees to log their weekly Timesheets.

Implemented UI design of timesheet management system with the help of SASS and Material UI from Figma screens.

Implemented admin and user role routing

Worked with React hook form to create complex forms with modal pop-ups from Material

Worked on bug fixes



SKILLS

languages

HTML5 · CSS3 · Javascript · Typescript · SQL

Frontend Tools

React.js · React Native · Next.js. ·

Electron.js · Redux · Context API ·

React-Hook-Form · Material UI ·

Bootstrap · Jquery

Backend Tools

Node.js · Express.js · MongoDB ·

Mongoose.js · Prisma ORM · Mysql ·

RestAPI

Deployment

Digital Occean · CentOS · NGINX ·

Lets Encrpt · Goddady ·

AWS Code Commit · Git

Operating Systems

MacOs · Linux · Windows

LANGUAGES

Hindi

English Proficient •••••

Native





PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

10/2023 - Present

OZZI (Mobile APP)

US

- Technologies: React Native, Redux, Node.js, PortgreSQL, GCP App Name : Ozzi Global Travel and Safety (Play Stote and App Store)

Production support responsibilities are given to me to manage Ozzi mobile app full stack. Ozzi mobile app frontend is build using react native, so currently working on its android version target SDK level upgrade as per the latest version specified by google. Also communication with apple and google support in parallel when ever required.

EDUCATION

BE, Elec and Telecom Engg - 62.38%

2015 - 2019

G N Sapkal College of Engg

Nashik, Maharashtra

DIPLOMA, Elect and Telecom Engg - 60.04%

2011 - 2015

S E S Education Society

Dhule, Maharashtra